M Usman Maqbool Bhutta

PHD CANDIDATE · DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Room 2008 (25), Robotics Institute, 2nd Floor, CYT Building, Lift(35-36), HKUST

🛮 (+852) 6843-2892 | 🗷 mumbhutta@connect.ust.hk | 🐐 usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🛅 usmanmaqbool | 🖏 usman17888

"Do it with passion or not at all."

Summary

Current co-founder of a start-up company Lisee Technology Corporation. 5+ years experience specializing in project management for research and development, web development and marketing at Friends Corporate Technologies. I have been a part of some other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. A super nerd who loves entrepreneurship, deep learning, and enjoys to develop the idea to reality. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises..

Education

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

Sep. 2016 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Electronic & Computer Engineering

- Got PEEF Pakistan scholarship to pursuing my studies
- · Research interests; Multi-Agent SLAM System and autonomous car driving

Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: 1st Division (80% Marks)

Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

- 2nd position in batch
- Grade: 1 st Division (74.6% marks)

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

Bahauddin Zakariya University - BZU

B.Sc. IN MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

Multan, Pakistan Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

· Grade: 1st Division

Research Publications

PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

BHUTTA, M. USMAN MAQBOOL, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Accepted in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems.

An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

BHUTTA, M. USMAN MAQBOOL, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP).

Efficient Reset Design Techniques

Journal Paper

Qamar, Zoha, Bushra Yaseen, and Usman Maqbool

2015

Published in Science International Lahore

Work Experience

INDUSTRY

Friends Corporate Technologies

Islamabad, PK

CEO

Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

Federal Government of Pakistan

Islamabad, PK May 2012 - Feb 2013

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC Islamabad, PK PHP DEVELOPER Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

ACADEMIC

Department of Computer Science

BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

Department of Physics

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

Aug. 2014 - Apr. 2016

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

Academic Activities _____

2018	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	IROS 2018
S 2018	Teaching Assistant , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
S 2017	Teaching Assistant, ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

May, 2018 Best Proposal Audience Award , Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Nov, 2017 Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
May, 2017 Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Dec, 2016 Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
Nov, 2016 Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

DOMESTIC

Sep 2013	Participant , Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Oct 2012	Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK
Oct 2011	Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK
Sep 2011	Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK
Apr 2011	Completion Award, Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2011	Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2010	Instuctor of short Course, PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2008	Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK

JUNE 28, 2018